Guide to the Vassar College Office of the Treasurer Records, 1861-1973 (bulk 1861-1934)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Office of the Treasurer Records
1861-1973
1861-1934
Vassar College. Office of the Treasurer
approximately 48 cubic feet (155 volumes, 29 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
This collection contains materials relating to the financial and business operations of Vassar College, primarily records kept by the Treasurer, Cashier, Accountant, and other administrators involved in college expenses and accounts.
Administrative History
The position of College Treasurer was established in 1861 as an officer of the Vassar College Board of Trustees, with Matthew Vassar, Jr., serving as the first Treasurer from 1861 until his death in 1881. The Treasurer managed most of Vassar College's finances until 1922, when the position of Comptroller (later renamed Controller in 1991) was established. The Comptroller reported to the Treasurer until 1927, when it became its own office, separate from the Treasurer. The position of Cashier was not officially established until 1931, reporting to the Comptroller.
In 1966, the Vice President of Finance and Administration was created to oversee a number of financial roles for the college. The Office of the Comptroller was overseen at various times between 1966 and 1985 by either the Vice President of Finance and Administration or the Office of the Treasurer.
Chronology of Vassar College Treasurers, 1861-1962
Matthew Vassar, Jr., 1861-1881 (Treasurer)
Willard L. Dean, 1882-1883 (Registrar and Assistant Treasurer)
Willard L. Dean, 1883-1893 (Treasurer and Registrar)
Willard L. Dean, 1893-1898 Oct (Treasurer and Secretary to the Board of Trustees)
Edward Elsworth, 1898-1903 (Treasurer and Secretary to the Board of Trustees)
Edward Elsworth, 1903-1910 (Treasurer)
Henry V. Pelton, 1910-1911 (Treasurer)
Will Hazen Boughton, C.E., 1911-1915 (Treasurer)
George Washington Polk, 1912-1921 (Assistant Treasurer)
George Washington Polk, 1921-1922 (Acting Treasurer; promoted to Comptroller in 1922)
Herbert Reed Gurney, A.B., 1915-1921 (Treasurer)
Arthur L. Lesher, 1922-1927 (Treasurer)
Ray Morris, 1927-1928 (Treasurer)
Raymond G. Guernsey, 1928-1940 (Treasurer and Counsel)
David G. Dutton, 1940-1941 (Treasurer)
John Wilkie, 1941-1962 (Treasurer)
George T. Welch, 1941-1962 (Assistant Treasurer)
George T. Welch, 1962- (Treasurer)
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains materials relating to the financial and business operations of Vassar College, primarily records kept by the Treasurer, Cashier, Accountant, and other administrators involved in college expenses and accounts. Records include financial ledgers and journals, including: cash books; day books; account ledgers for students, offices, departments, and businesses with whom Vassar obtained goods or services; deposit book; expense books; investment books; and other miscellaneous bookkeeping records. Also included are receipts and vouchers of financial transactions, as well as correspondence of the treasurer and other administrators under the purview of the Office of the Treasurer.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Series I. Financial Record Books, 1861-1973; Series II. Receipts and Vouchers, [1865?] - circa 1902; and Series III. Administrative Files, 1876-1925.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Office of the Controller
Vassar College Vice President of Finance and Administration
Subject Headings
Names:
Dean, Willard L., -1898; Polk, George Washington, 1855-1931; Vassar, Matthew, Jr., 1809-1881
Organizations:
Vassar College--Administration; Vassar College--Faculty; Vassar College--Finances; Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie
Document Types:
Correspondence; Financial records; Minutes (administrative records); Reports
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Administrative Offices and Functions
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, February 2025.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from various sources, including the Office of the Controller and long-term storage, 2004-2024. (A2004-019, A2008-028, A2017-012, A2024-003, A2024-017)
Series List
- Series I. Financial Record Books, 1861-1973; [145 volumes, 3 boxes]
  Arranged alphabetically by item or file title.
- Series II. Receipts and Vouchers, [1865?] - circa 1902; [9 volumes, 13 boxes]
  Arranged alphabetically by file title.
- Series III. Administrative Files, 1876-1925; [1 volume, 13 boxes]
Container List
- Series I. Financial Record Books, 1861-1973; [145 volumes, 3 boxes]
  - Account Book - Outside Businesses, 1882 May - 1889 Aug; [31 x 14 x 4 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized by name.
  - Accounts Journal - General and Students, School Supplies, 1878 Jul - 1881 Jun; [43 x 18 x 5 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized alphabetically by account, no index.
  - Accounts Journal - Students and Faculty, 1929-1933 (Bound Volumes)
    Sections include: Faculty, faculty charges, faculty laundry, and student laundry.
  - Accounts Journal - Students and Faculty, School Supplies, 1887-1891 (Bound Volumes)
    Organized alphabetically by name.
  - Accounts Journal - Students and Faculty, School Supplies, 1891 Sep - 1893 Mar (Bound Volumes)
  - Accounts Journal - Students, Music books and scores, 1875 - circa 1881 (Bound Volumes)
  - Accounts Journal - Students, Music, books, and supplies, 1893-1899; [36 x 23 x 5 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Aid Distribution Book,", 1890-1924 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Application Fee Registers,", [1922-1939?]; [2 volumes] (Box 3)
  - "Book of Wills,", circa 1891 (Bound Volumes)
    Handwritten transcripts of wills featuring bequests to Vassar College, 1868-1889. Includes Edward L. Beadle (p. 63), Stephen M. Buckingham (p. 93), Jacob P. Giraud (p. 29), Warren J. Merrill (p. 145), John Guy Vassar (p. 109), Matthew Vassar (p. 3), and Matthew Vassar, Jr. (p. 39).
  - "Cash [Contributions?] Book,", 1861 Apr 9 - 1872 May 18 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Accounts Book,", 1866 Jan 24 - 1904 Oct 14 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Accounts Book - Students,", 1870 Jul - 1871 Jun; [35 x 22 x 4 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized alphabetically.
  - Cash Book, 1865 Sep 18 - 1866 Jul 24 (Box 1)
    General, organized chronologically.
  - Cash Book, 1866 Sep 6 - 1870 Sep 29 (Box 1)
  - Cash Book, 1870 Oct 3 - 1874 Sep 3 (Box 1)
  - "Cash Book,", 1874 Sep 3 - 1880 Jul 20; [41 x 19 x 5 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book,", 1880 Jul 21 - 1885 Sep 30; [33 x 23 x 5 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Cash Book, 1885 Oct 1 - 1890 Oct 13; [36 x 25 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book,", 1890 Oct 13 - 1895 Mar 1 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book,", 1895 Mar 1 - 1895 Jul 26; [41 x 28 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book No. 1,", 1895 Jul 1 - 1897 Jul 23; [42 x 31 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Receipts and disbursements, organized chronologically.
  - "Cash Book No. 2,", 1897 Jul 24 - 1898 Jun 3 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book No. 3,", 1898 Jun 4 - 1900 Jan 31; [42 x 33 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book No. 4,", 1900 Feb 1 - 1901 Jun 29; [41 x 33 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book No. 8,", 1907 Jun 13 - 1908 Dec 31; [43 x 35 x 9 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Book No. 9,", 1909 Jan 2 - 1911 Feb 4; [45 x 37 x 8 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Cash by month, organized chronologically.
  - "Cash Book No. 10,", 1911-1913 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Cash Journal,", 1881 Feb 22 - 1886 Apr 17; [40 x 29 x 7 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized chronologically.
  - "Cash Journal,", 1919 Jul 10 - 1925 Jun 30; [40 x 52 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Central Ledger, with index,", 1874 Sep - 1878 Jul; [47 x 35 x 10 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized alphabetically by account.
  - "Central Ledger,", 1895-1900; [51 x 51 x 16 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
    p. 1-699 Student accounts, p. 700-917 College, faculty, and misc accounts, p. 1299-1360 Surplus accounts, room deposits, p. 1399-1400 deposit account.
  - "College Accounts Ledger No. 1, with index,", 1865 Sep - 1867 Aug (Bound Volumes)
  - "College Accounts Ledger No. 2, with index,", 1867 Sep - 1969 Jul; [42 x 30 x 7 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "College Accounts Ledger No. 3, with index,", 1869 Sep - 1871 Sep (Bound Volumes)
  - "College Accounts Ledger No. 4, with index,", 1871 Sep - 1873 Jul; [41 x 30 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "College Accounts Ledger No. 5, with index,", 1873 Sep - 1874 Jul; [46 x 34 x 11 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 1, 1873 Mar 29 - 1875 Jul 25 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 2, 1875 Jul 27 - 1876 Nov 29 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 3, 1876 Dec 1 - 1878 Oct 31 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 4, 1878 Nov 1 - 1880 Jul 31 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 5, 1880 Aug 2 - 1882 Sep 26 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 6, 1882 Sep 27 - 1884 Jun 16 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 7, 1884 Jun 24 - 1886 Apr 16 (Box 1)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 8, 1886 Apr 19 - 1888 Jan 4 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 9, 1888 Jan 5 - 1889 Jun 18 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 10, 1889 Jun 19 - 1891 Feb 20 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 11, 1891 Feb 23 - 1892 Jun 3 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 12, 1892 Jun 4 - 1893 Sep 21 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 13, 1893 Sep 22 - 1894 Sep 22 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 1, No. 14, 1894 Sep 22 - 1895 Jun 25 (Box 2)
  - "Day Book" - Set 2, No. 1, 1873 Aug - 1876 Oct; [41 x 22 x 7 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Day Book - Set 2, No. 2, 1876 Oct 10 - 1881 Feb 21; [41 x 29 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Day Book - Set 3, No. 1, 1891 Dec 11 - 1892 Sep 30 (Box 2)
  - Day Book - Set 3, No. 2, 1892 Sep 26 - 1893 Jan 5 (Box 2)
  - Day Book, 1872 Jan 8 - 1880 Sep 20; [40 x 17 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Day Book, 1874 Jul 11 - 1886 Jul 27; [40 x 18 x 4 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Day Book, 1886 Mar 1 - 1895 Jun 29 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Day Book - Board and Tuition Accounts,", 1871 Sep - 1873 Dec; [41 x 23 x 7 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Departmental Accounts, 1923-1925; [36 x 44 x 3 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Departmental Expenses Ledger,", 1923-1924 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Departmental Expenses Ledger,", 1924-1925 (Bound Volumes)
  - Departmental Expenses Ledger - Music Dept, 1884 Sep 18 - 1899 May 18 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Deposit Ledger No. 1, with index,", 1874 Jul - 1887 Nov (Bound Volumes)
  - "Deposit Ledger No. 2 - Students,", 1888-1900 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Deposit Ledger No. 3 - Students,", 1900-1902 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Deposit Ledger No. 10 - College Functions,", 1900-1910 (Bound Volumes)
  - Financial Ledger - "Tuesday Thursday Saturday,", 1864 Nov - 1865 Apr (Bound Volumes)
  - "Fund Ledger No. 1,", 1874 Jul - 1892 Jul (Bound Volumes)
    Organized by fund.
  - "Fund Ledger No. 2,", 1891 Nov - 1900 Jul (Bound Volumes)
  - "Fund Ledger No. 3,", 1901 Jul - 1916 Jul (Bound Volumes)
  - "Fund Ledger No. 4,", 1916 Jul - 1925 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "Fund Ledger No. 5,", 1925 Jun - 1934 Jul (Bound Volumes)
  - Funds Journal, 1861 Feb - 1874 Jul; [37 x 26 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized alphabetically by fund, with index.
  - Funds Journal, 1861 Feb - 1874 Jul; [37 x 26 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Funds Journal - Cash No. 1,", 1925 Jul - 1931 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "Funds Journal - Cash No. 2,", 1931 Jul - 1935 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "Funds Journal No. 1,", 1874 Jun 13 - 1894 Jan 22 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Funds Journal No. 2,", 1894 Feb 5 - 1904 Dec 24 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Funds Journal No. 3,", 1905 Jan - 1919 Oct (Bound Volumes)
  - Funds Ledger, 1925 Nov - 1929 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger, 1882 Jan 3 - 1886 Sep 4; [42 x 36 x 3 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 1, 1925 Jul - 1926 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 2, 1926 Jul - 1927 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 3, 1927 Jul - 1928 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 4, 1928 Jul - 1929 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 5, 1929 Jul - 1930 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 6, 1930 Jul - 1931 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 7, 1931 Jul - 1932 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 8, 1932 Aug - 1933 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 9, 1933 Aug - 1934 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - General Ledger - Daily, Vol. 1, 1892 Nov 15 - 1910 Jun 30 (Bound Volumes)
  - General Ledger - Daily, Vol. 2, 1910 Jul 26 - 1923 May 31 (Bound Volumes)
  - General Ledger - Daily, Vol. 3, 1923 Jun 8 - 1928 Jun 30 (Bound Volumes)
  - General Ledger - Daily, Vol. 4, 1928 Jul 1 - 1932 Jun 30 (Bound Volumes)
  - [General Ledger?] No. 7 - Index, circa 1880-1889; [49 x 36 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "General Ledger No. 10 - Index,", 1900-1910 (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "General Ledger No. 11,", 1910 Jul - 1916 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "General Ledger No. 11 - Index,", 1910-1916 (Bound Volumes)
  - "General Ledger No. 12,", 1916 Jul - 1922 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "General Ledger No. 13,", 1922 Jul - 1925 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "General Ledger No. 14,", 1925 Jul - 1928 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "General Ledger No. 15,", 1928 Jul - 1934 Jun (Bound Volumes)
  - "Insurance Book,", 1901-1917 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Insurances Ledger,", 1877-1888; [41 x 28 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Investments Book,", 1884-1937 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Investments Book,", 1887 - circa 1938 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Jewett House Expenditures,", 1938-1973 (Box 3)
  - "Laundry Register,", 1883-1884 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Laundry Register,", 1884-1885 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Laundry Register,", 1917 Sep - 1925 Jun; [36 x 24 x 4 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Payroll Ledger,", 1878 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Payroll Ledger,", 1887 Aug - 1893 Feb (Bound Volumes)
  - "Payroll Ledger,", 1893 Mar - 1896 May (Bound Volumes)
  - "Petty Cash Book, Vol. 1,", 1920 Jul 21 - 1924 Mar 6; [32 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Petty Cash Book, Vol. 2,", 1924 Mar 7 - 1925 Jun 30; [32 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Postal Expenses Ledger,", 1905 Jul - 1909 Oct (Box 3)
  - "Records of articles for safekeeping, and returned,", 1901-1935 (Bound Volumes)
    Ledger of physical objects of value.
  - "Register of stock holdings and transactions,", 1864-1865 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Salary Register,", 1924-1925 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Steward's Account Book,", 1865 Sep - 1876 Jul; [43 x 37 x 3 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    "Articles bought for the Steward's Dept" (food, soap, etc.)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 1, 1900 Sep - 1901 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 2, 1901 Jul - 1902 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 3, 1902-1903; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 4, 1903 Sep - 1904 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 5, 1904 Aug - 1905 Jul; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 6, 1905 Sep - 1906 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 7, 1906-1907; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 8, 1907-1908; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 9, 1908-1909; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 10, 1909-1910; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 11, 1910 Sep - 1911 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 12, 1911-1912; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 13, 1912 Sep - 1913 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 14, 1913-1914; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 15, 1914-1915; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 16, 1915-1916; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 17, 1916 Sep - 1917 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 18, 1917-1918; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 19, 1918-1919; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 21, 1920 Sep - 1921 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 22, 1921-1922; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 23, 1922 Sep - 1923 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 24, 1923-1924; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 25, 1924-1925; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 26, 1925 Sep - 1926 Aug; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 27, 1926-1927; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 28, 1927-1928; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 29, 1928 Sep - 1929 Jul; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 31, 1930-1931; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 32, 1931 Aug - 1932 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 33, 1932 Sep - 1933 Jun; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - Student Accounts Ledger - Annual, Vol. 34, 1933 Sep - 1934 Jul; [41 x 27 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes)
  - "Student Accounts Ledger No. 1,", 1900-1902; [150 x 44 x 11 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "Student Accounts Ledger No. 1 - Index,", circa 1900; [48 x 39 x 2 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "Student Expense Accounts,", circa 1886 - 1896; [39 x 28 x 4 cm] (Bound Volumes)
    Organized by enrollment year, then alphabetically by student.
  - "Subsistence Department Ledger No. 13,", 1914 Jun - 1915 Jun; [42 x 69 x 9 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "Tray Ledger - Cushing House,", 1920-1936 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Tray Ledger - Lathrop House and Main Building,", 1903-1932 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Tray Ledger - Josselyn House,", 1912-1936 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Tray Ledger - North Hall (Jewett House),", undated (Bound Volumes)
  - "Tray Ledger - Strong House,", 1903-1931 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Tray Ledger - Raymond House and Davison House,", 1903-1932 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Treasurer's Statements No. 1 - Cash,", 1886 Sep - 1890 Dec; [43 x 45 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "Treasurer's Statements No. 2,", 1891 Jan 2 - 1894 Oct 31; [43 x 46 x 6 cm] (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - "Tuition Fee Accounts Ledger, Vol. 1,", 1867 Jun - 1869 Aug (Bound Volumes)
  - "Tuition Fee Accounts Ledger, Vol. 2,", 1869 Sep - 1871 Jul (Bound Volumes)
- Series II. Receipts and Vouchers, [1865?] - circa 1902; [9 volumes, 13 boxes]
  - Receipt Book, 1870s (Bound Volumes)
  - Receipt Book, 1875 Oct-Nov (Bound Volumes)
  - Receipt Book, 1877-1878 (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - Receipt Book, 1883-1885 (Bound Volumes)
  - Receipt Book, 1887-1888 (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - Receipt Book, 1888-1889 (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - Receipt Book, 1890-1891 (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - Receipt Book, 1891-1892 (Bound Volumes (Oversize))
  - Receipt Book, 1893-1895 (Bound Volumes)
  - Receipt Book, 1894 (Bound Volumes)
  - "Register of Audited Vouchers,", circa 1902 (Bound Volumes)
  - Voucher index, #19000-30000, undated (Box 3)
  - Vouchers A, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers B, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers C, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers D, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers E, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers F, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers F, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers G, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers G, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers H, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers H, undated; [1 box]
  - Vouchers I, undated; [1 box]
- Series III. Administrative Files, 1876-1925; [1 volume, 13 boxes]
  - Correspondence book of Willard L. Dean related to College purchases, 1876-1883 (Bound Volumes)
  - Files, budgets, correspondence, 1880s-1920s; [1 box]
  - Files and correspondence, 1910-1925; [1 box]
  - Files and correspondence, 1915; [1 box]
  - Files and correspondence, 1916; [1 box]
  - Minutes and Reports, 1917-1966; [1 box]
  - Records of George Washington Polk, 1925-1928; [1 box]
  - Cashier's records, undated; [7 boxes]